MEDICAL LABORATORY SCIENTIST II

Summary

Skilled, detail-oriented certified Medical Technologist with twenty three years of experience in Microbiology especially Parasitology working on Blood & Intestinal Parasite, Environmental Microbiology Laboratory during the past two years and competent background in Serology & Immunology, Hematology, chemistry and extensive experience in Mycobacteriology. Lead experience in Parasitology assisting the Microbiology manager for the past three years. Demonstrate excellence customer service aspect and patient satisfaction. Maintain in-dept. knowledge of technical principles, instrument operation.

Skills

- Prior supervisory experience
- Experience in Microbiology
- Computer proficient
- Serology, HIV/AIDS, Hepatitis
- Problem solving ability
- Parasitology Strong background
- Demonstrate Excellent Customer Service
- Quality Control & Quality Assurance
- Laboratory's Trainer for Students
- Molecular Experience (PCR)
- Aptitude to write for publication
- Mycobacteriology extensive experience

Experience

September 2011 to July 2017

Atlantic Health System Warren Medical Laboratory Scientist II

- Work on rotation basis over Environmental Microbiology Lab., Parasitology, Virology and Serology My routine responsibilities in Parasitology are working on Quality Assurance and Quality Control, maintaining inventory of expendable supplies.
- Participate in the performance of proficiency test.
- Train and retrain employees, and student as required.
- Approve test results.
- Assist the Lab manager with all administrative and technical aspects of laboratory operation.
- Collecting Data, test statistics and prepare reports as needed.
- Ability to submit ideas for annual report when needed.
- Performing sample for Blood, and Intestinal Parasites using SED-CONNECT, Zinc Sulfate, and Para-Pak Stool Concentration Method to identify, diagnose.
- In the Environmental Laboratory department, performing technical work preparing and performing chemical, and bacteriological laboratory analysis on Potable (drinking) water samples, and Non-Potable water from beaches researching Total Coliform, Fecal coliform Escherichia Coli using Colilert and Heterotrophic Plate Counts (HPCs).
- Receives, and logs samples; prepares, calibrates and maintain Laboratory Equipment; follow the NELAC Institute (TNI) guidelines and Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) regulations complying with laboratory standards Operating Procedures (SOPs) and safety procedures.
- Maintains and enters accurate data records into the Laboratory Information Management System (LIMS), Citrix access gateway_ Labware7.
- Works Serology Department performing Syphilis screening by Becton Dickenson Macro-Vue RPR cards, Phoenix Trep-Sure EIA micro wells for Antibody detection to confirm the presence of Treponema Pallidum.
- In case of discrepancies on the above two test, recourse to Serodia®_TP-PA with his lipoid antigen offers the advantage of gelatin
 particles which eliminate non-specific reactions with plasma specimen.
- In Virology department performing Hepatitis Screening using Ortho diagnostic system using ECiQ, 3600, Architect Equipment using all markers, HAV, HBc, HBSAb, HCV.
- Approve Hepatitis, RPR, and EIA result when required.
- On HIV-Lab experience on Nucleic Acid Testing (NAAT) / APTIMA HIV-1 RNA Qual, as well VIRAL Load / m2000sp and m2000rt;
 ABBOTT Equipment and Facs COUNT CD4/CD8 machine experience acquiert in the Main Branch in Jacksonville Laboratory Miami
 Dade County Health Department working in STD, Family Planning, TB_ January 2011_September 2011 Working on moderate
 Complexity testing; Reading of Neisseria Gonorrhea stained slides, KOH reaction, Treponema Pallidum microscopic organism detection, performs BD macro-Vue Tests Cards, Rapid HIV, HGC detection on pregnant women.
- Drawing Blood sample by venipuncture.

March 2007 to December 2010

Avantor Valencia, CA Lab Services Coordinator

• Assigning work to the Phlebotomist to draw blood and Lab Assistant to proper integrity and distribution of specimens, Communicate effectively with Physician, and all Healthcare Professional.

March 2007 to January 2010 Lab Microbiologist Assistant

- Processing on all microbiology specimens including all Body Fluids, tissue, Load and unloaded Blood Culture on the Bactec machine 9000MB 9240
- Perform rapid test Flu A&B, Mono Test, Rotavirus, CSF panel, Strep B, and Rapid HIV.

October 2004 to March 2006

Community Health System Sarasota, FL Medical Technologist

- Detection and Quantification of Cryptosporidium by Real Time PCR Nested PCR used to detect Cryptosporidium Parvum, C.
- bailey and C.
- serpentis by gel electrophoresis.
- Restriction enzyme digest vspI used to distinguish C.Parvum genotypes I and 2.
- Rectriction enzyme digest II used to distinguish C.Parvum from C.baileyi and C.serpentis.
- Detection of Pneumocystis carinii by gene amplification.
- Concentration of Oocyst of Cryptosporidium parvum in water sample using a fragment rRNA 18S of 300bp.
- Identification of Clostridium Difficile by ELISA.
- Multiplex PCR for Enteroaggregative E.Coli detection and identification using three plasmid-borne genes (aggregative adherence AA probe, Aap, AggR).
- Qualitative detection Lactoferrin on IBD-Check and IBD Scan by Elisa for quantitative detective of elevated levels of lactoferrin.
- Leuko test for direct detection of Lactoferrin.
- Sub Control Strains on positive Lactoferrin stool samples Medical Technologist at working at GHESKIO Centers (Haitian Study Group of Kaposi's sarcoma and Opportunistic Infections); P-au-P, Haiti from February 1994 - October 2005 Culturing Blood via Bactec, Enteric and Neisseria Gonorrhea by APi and Vitek-2 machine: Microbiology.
- HIV & Hepatitis screening using Abbott, Mini Vidas, Pasteur and Murex equip.
- confirm by Western Blot.
- Syphillis Screening test using RPR and TPHA and also confirmatory test using EIA, and FTA: Serology Department.
- Coulter Equipment 690, 750: Hematology Department.
- Acid Fast bacilli (AFB) screening and drug susceptibility and sensitivity testing was perform after Sodium Hydroxide or Lauryl sulfate digestion, decontamination and concentration using the standard proportionate technique: TB Lab _ Mycobacteriology.
- Parasites identification by sedimentation using a formalin concentration technique, Ethyl Acetate or and Flotation and Kato Techniques, Kinyoun Stain for AFB and Iodine for the protozoa: Parasitology.
- Urinalysis testing.

Education and Training

Medical Laboratory Sciences Associates of Science Medical Laboratory Sciences

Faculty of Medicine & Pharmacology and Medical Laboratory Sciences, Port-au-Prince, Haiti *Training in Cornell University & New York Hospital: Blood Parasite, Mycobacteria *Training in (CHU) Centre Hospitalier Universitaire d'Amiens (France) Mycology, Parasitology *Florida Atlantic University (FAU) Biotechnology Certificate Program *CDC Training on Blood Parasites, Intestinal Organism & Arthropods and Molecular Pathology

National Institute of Administration

Public Administration Bachelor Degree Public Administration & Management, P-au-P, Haiti *Biological Sciences study Miami Dade College in progress

Personal Information

Abstracts & Posters submission Subject: "Improved diagnostic of Cryptosporidium and Microsporidia infections by PCR in patients with AIDS and diarrhea in Haiti", Organization: America Society of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene (ASTMH) Location: Atlanta/Georgia Date: November 12-16, 2006

Interests

Licensures and Affiliation, State of Florida American Association of Bio Analyst (AAB) and American Medical Technologist (AMT) Board of Registry License# TN 42454 Medical Technologist [Microbiology, Serology/Immunology, Hematology, Chemistry, Immunohematology] Skills

Acid, administrative, APi, Architect, Agency, Biotechnology, Drawing Blood, draw blood, C, Citrix, Excellent Customer Service, EIA, ELISA, Environmental Protection, Fast, gateway, Hematology, maintaining inventory, Laboratory Equipment, LIMS, Laboratory Information Management System, MB, access, 2000, Works, Murex, Pathology, PCR, Pharmacology, Phlebotomist, Prince, Problem solving, progress, publication, Quality Control, Quality Assurance, Reading, Real Time, researching, safety, SED, statistics, supervisory experience, Trainer, Urinalysis, venipuncture

Additional Information

- Licensures and Affiliation, State of Florida American Association of Bio Analyst (AAB) and American Medical Technologist (AMT) Board
 of Registry License# TN 42454 Medical Technologist [Microbiology, Serology/Immunology, Hematology, Chemistry, Immunohematology]
- Accomplishments Abstracts & Posters submission Subject: "Improved diagnostic of Cryptosporidium and Microsporidia infections by PCR in patients with AIDS and diarrhea in Haiti", Organization: America Society of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene (ASTMH) Location: Atlanta/Georgia Date: November 12-16, 2006